[Music]
eating for muscle hypertrophy basically
comes down to two important items
number one you have to be in caloric
surplus
i've seen a lot of people make a major
mistake when they do this
they think i want to grow muscle i have
to eat more and so they dramatically
increase the caloric intake
i'm talking double maybe even triple the
amount of calories they normally eat
well yes this helps but i don't think it
helps most people get the goal they're
really truly after
see most of us when we say we want to
grow muscle we mean we want to grow
lean muscle in other words we want to
add muscle but we don't want to add a
lot of extra fat
so if your goal is to just optimize
muscle growth then yes you need to be
maybe
20 50 maybe 60 caloric surplus
but a lot of that muscle is going to
come with a lot of unnecessary fat
i guess if you're trying to compete and
maximize muscle growth and bodybuilding
or something and you're
going to go through a phase where you
get as big as possible and you cut a lot
of fat down
fine but for most people who want to
gain mostly lean mass
say you want to gain 10 pounds of muscle
well you can't gain 10 pounds of muscle
and no
fat but you want to gain 10 pounds of
muscle and you'd be like cool with one
extra pound of fat or two extra pounds
well the rate the research we have now
suggests that you only want to be in
about a 10 to 15 percent caloric surplus
now if you're a beginner you might be
able to go up to like 20 percent
but that's really about it i know some
folks like eric helms and others are
doing some
some more research in this because we
don't exactly this is not 100
set but this is what we understand as of
now so if you have normally 2 000
calories and that just keeps you
at the same body weight as well as same
amount of leanness
then you need to go up to like 220 maybe
200 or 2000
2200 2300 that's it it's one extra meal
right you don't need to add an extra
thousand if you do that again
a higher percentage of your increase in
size will come from fat than you
probably want
so you probably can get that by just
boosting up your carbohydrate or your
fat depending on where you specifically
lie
these are general numbers people hit in
terms of amount of carbohydrate and fat
i don't really care which one you boost
up as long as you're at kind of these
minimum thresholds
and there's a lot of wiggle room here
these ones aren't in my opinion as
critical
the second big thing you have to get is
the protein okay
so if you take your normal diet and you
make sure that you're having a minimum
amount of protein
maybe scooch it up a little bit maybe
push the pro the carbohydrates
and fat up but don't go up too high okay
what you you can survive having a little
bit lower carbohydrate
and a little bit lower fat but you can't
survive low protein for the most part if
you're trying to maximize the muscle
growth
so here are some numbers to aim for
having said that there's been a lot of
research
again at this like three even four grams
per kilogram body weight suggesting that
it really is helpful at adding lean
tissue so i don't think there's any
reason
to really want to be much below this two
grams per kilogram body weight which is
effectively one gram per pound
in my opinion that's the low end of the
recommendation
get at least there if not higher and i
see really no reason if you're trying to
really get lean
and grow muscle rather to not be you
know two and a half
maybe even three grams per kilogram okay
within that then you have to make sure
you're getting
around 0.4 grams of high quality
protein per feeding now the research
would suggest you could be a little bit
lower but i think
there's no reason to go below this 0.4
grams this would then translate into
something like 20 to 50 grams
of feeding grams of protein per feeding
now hq stands for high quality this
means a complete protein
this is not peanut butter this is not
broccoli this is
google complete protein you need them
all there because you need
the essential amino acids those are what
drive muscle hypertrophy
and you specifically need leucine and
you want somewhere in the neighborhood
of 700 to 300 milligrams of leucine per
feeding
and you also want to combine that with
other the other essential amino acids
so if you eat most of your protein
coming from whole foods
you're gonna get almost all these boxes
checked if you want to add some
supplemental protein powders
things like that on the outside just
fine if you are eating a lot
or like a lot of plant-based proteins or
a small percentage
of animal proteins then you probably
need to bump these these numbers up even
higher because you're
going to have a more difficult time
getting that leucine threshold okay
now we still have a bunch of unresolved
questions like timing
and feeding numbers so do you have to
eat six
seven eight meals a day i don't think so
as long as you can get your numbers with
three meals i think you're just fine
what about one to two meals
i don't know i guess it's possible if
you hit the numbers
my gut is it won't be the same for most
people i think you
need to get at least three separate
feedings because of how transient
protein is
but we don't know right research is open
on that topic
in terms of the timing i've already
covered this in a 25 minute fizz video
so you'd have to go back to this but i
actually think i have a five minute as
well
i can't remember all right the post
exercise anabolic window like i was just
saying
it doesn't necessarily matter that you
have the protein directly after
your workout as long as you have it in
the system but again you want more
detail on that go check that video out
i would lastly i would recommend that
you read this article by alan aragon and
brad schoenfeld
this is through the nsca strength
conditioning journal it's a fantastic
very practitioner based
it's not original research there's not
stats and methods and stuff like that
it's just
what do we know scientifically about
nutrition for maximizing body
composition so in and out in uh you know
five ish minutes or so if you really
like this and this was your jam i would
strongly encourage you to check out my
big
long three-part series on the physiology
the stimuli and especially
if you're just want the practical stuff
part three where i cover over an hour of
exactly what to eat
how to train volume intensity frequency
negatives eccentrics
all that stuff in that video all right
we'll see you there
[Music]
you